[
  {
    "question": "What's the maximum O2 flow rate that you can provide using nasal prongs?",
    "options": [
      "a) 10 liter/min",
      "b) 0.5 liter/min",
      "c) 4 liter/min",
      "d) 2 liter/min",
      "e) 7 liter/min"
    ],
    "answer": "c) 4 liter/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common complication that follows chronic otitis media with effusion is:",
    "options": [
      "a) Meningitis",
      "b) Mastoiditis",
      "c) Permanent nerve deafness",
      "d) Brain abscess",
      "e) Impaired speech and language development"
    ],
    "answer": "e) Impaired speech and language development"
  },
  {
    "question": "Significant number of children with the following conditions is infected with Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV):",
    "options": [
      "a) Acute otitis media",
      "b) Bronchiolitis",
      "c) Acute diarrheal disease",
      "d) Acute myocarditis",
      "e) Follicular tonsillitis"
    ],
    "answer": "b) Bronchiolitis"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 15 months old child presented with drooling, difficulty feeding and stridor for 24 hours. Temp 40°C. He was diagnosed with epiglottitis. Which one of the following is true regarding the management of this condition?",
    "options": [
      "A) Spatula (tongue depressor) examination is mandatory to confirm the diagnosis",
      "B) Intravenous benzyl penicillin is the drug of choice",
      "C) Tracheostomy is not indicated",
      "D) Chemoprophylaxis is recommended for household contacts of all ages",
      "E) Intravenous Ceftriaxone is indicated"
    ],
    "answer": "E) Intravenous Ceftriaxone is indicated"
  },
  {
    "question": "18 months presents with stridor and barking cough, he looks irritable and has central cyanosis; the mother reported a change in voice. What is the best treatment?",
    "options": [
      "a) Intravenous broad spectrum antibiotics",
      "b) Nebulized short acting salbutamol",
      "c) Immediate tracheostomy",
      "d) Rigid bronchoscope",
      "e) Racemic epinephrine and oxygen"
    ],
    "answer": "e) Racemic epinephrine and oxygen"
  },
  {
    "question": "3 years old unvaccinated child presents with high fever and stridor for 2 days, he looks unwell, open his mouth with drooling of saliva. What is the first step in his management?",
    "options": [
      "a) Start intravenous ceftriaxone",
      "b) Take pharyngeal swab and culture",
      "c) Secure the airway",
      "d) Examine the throat for evidence of discharge",
      "e) Obtain lateral neck x ray"
    ],
    "answer": "c) Secure the airway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an absolute indication for adenoidectomy?",
    "options": [
      "a) More than 3 attacks per year",
      "b) Patient wish",
      "c) Peritonsillar abscess",
      "d) Obstructive sleeping apnea",
      "e) Persistent voice change"
    ],
    "answer": "d) Obstructive sleeping apnea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is recognized as an indication for tonsillectomy?",
    "options": [
      "a) Attacks more than 2 per year",
      "b) Association with otitis media",
      "c) Snoring",
      "d) Quinsy",
      "e) Foul mouth odor"
    ],
    "answer": "d) Quinsy"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 2 years old boy accidentally drank kerosene. He coughed for several minutes and then vomited. He was brought to hospital after one hour with normal vitals. Most appropriate next step?",
    "options": [
      "a) Intravenous antibiotics",
      "b) Oral antibiotics and steroids",
      "c) Intravenous corticosteroids",
      "d) Reassurance and send home",
      "e) Salbutamol by nebulizer"
    ],
    "answer": "d) Reassurance and send home"
  },
  {
    "question": "A young infant is rushed to the emergency room. The child is cyanotic, gasping and has a heart rate of 40 per minute. Most appropriate immediate intervention?",
    "options": [
      "a) Intraosseous cannulation",
      "b) Synchronized cardioversion",
      "c) Chest compression",
      "d) 100% oxygen by face mask",
      "e) Open airway and Bag-mask ventilation"
    ],
    "answer": "e) Open airway and Bag-mask ventilation"
  },
  {
    "question": "You and your colleague are practicing CPR to an infant manikin in the skills laboratory. What’s the ratio of the chest compressions to positive pressure ventilations?",
    "options": [
      "a) 3 to 1",
      "b) 30 to 2",
      "c) 15 to 2",
      "d) 15 to 1",
      "e) 2 to 30"
    ],
    "answer": "c) 15 to 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 3 year old female presented with a chronic cough for 2 years, greenish sputum, fever, she lost 2 kg in the past one year and has chronic diarrhea. Investigation for diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "a) Abdominal CT",
      "b) High resolution CT",
      "c) Frontal sinus CT",
      "d) Sputum ZN",
      "e) Chloride Sweat test"
    ],
    "answer": "e) Chloride Sweat test"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the followings is not a feature of cystic fibrosis in infancy?",
    "options": [
      "a) Situs inversus",
      "b) Meconium ileus",
      "c) Prolonged jaundice",
      "d) Failure to thrive",
      "e) Steatorrhea"
    ],
    "answer": "a) Situs inversus"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 15 months old child was referred to the outpatient clinic because of a sudden onset of fast breathing while playing with kids. Examination: Temp 37.5 °C, RR 70/min, expiratory bronchi with diminished air entry in right chest. Diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "a) Bronchial asthma",
      "b) Bronchopneumonia",
      "c) Bronchiolitis",
      "d) Foreign body inhalation",
      "e) Heart Failure"
    ],
    "answer": "d) Foreign body inhalation"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 9 months old child with shortness of breath, runny nose and intermittent fever for 2 days. RR 64/min, chest indrawing, wheezes and scattered crepitations. Most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "a) Bronchopneumonia",
      "b) Lobar Pneumonia",
      "c) Bronchiolitis",
      "d) Heart Failure",
      "e) Bronchial asthma"
    ],
    "answer": "c) Bronchiolitis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding tuberculosis in children is NOT accurate?",
    "options": [
      "a) Children are not usually infectious",
      "b) 50% of exposed children are infected",
      "c) Disease in children is reticuloendothelial",
      "d) Phlyctenular conjunctivitis is manifestation of miliary TB",
      "e) Lymph nodes are the commonest extrapulmonary sites to be involved"
    ],
    "answer": "d) Phlyctenular conjunctivitis is manifestation of miliary TB"
  },
  {
    "question": "On long treatment of asthma, when LABA (long acting B2 agonist) is administered?",
    "options": [
      "a) Step 1",
      "b) Step 2",
      "c) Step 3",
      "d) Step 4",
      "e) Step 5"
    ],
    "answer": "c) Step 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "3 year old unvaccinated child presents with stridor and irritability, has high grade fever, mouth showed whitish membranes over the tonsils. Best modality of management?",
    "options": [
      "a) IV Ampicillin and gentamycin",
      "b) Tracheotomy",
      "c) Erythromycin and antitoxin",
      "d) Sedative and racemic epinephrine",
      "e) Antitoxin and intravenous fluid"
    ],
    "answer": "c) Erythromycin and antitoxin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the least useful in assessing the severity of an acute asthmatic attack in children?",
    "options": [
      "a) Tachycardia",
      "b) Pulsus paradoxus",
      "c) Fall in the respiratory rate",
      "d) Use of accessory muscles",
      "e) Impaired consciousness"
    ],
    "answer": "c) Fall in the respiratory rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "An 18 months old male presented with acute stridor. Most appropriate management?",
    "options": [
      "A) Nebulised adrenaline and Intramuscular dexamethasone",
      "B) Nebulised sodium acetylcystine",
      "C) Intravenous ceftriaxone",
      "D) Nebulised Salbutamol and Oxygen",
      "E) Low oxygen saturations"
    ],
    "answer": "A) Nebulised adrenaline and Intramuscular dexamethasone"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 10 years old boy is brought with a one week history of chest pain and fever. O/E: looks ill, RR 50/min, trachea central, right chest: reduced movements, reduced tactile vocal fremitus, dull percussion note. Most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "A) Right sided emphysema",
      "B) Right sided pneumothorax",
      "C) Collapsed right lung",
      "D) Right sided lobar pneumonia",
      "E) Right sided empyema"
    ],
    "answer": "E) Right sided empyema"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is the best indicator of life threatening asthma?",
    "options": [
      "A) Poor response to intravenous hydrocortisone",
      "B) Previous history of ICU admission",
      "C) Recurrent episodes of acute Asthma",
      "D) Persistent nocturnal Asthma",
      "E) Low oxygen saturations"
    ],
    "answer": "E) Low oxygen saturations"
  },
  {
    "question": "An 18-month-old child presents with snoring, breathing with an open mouth and failure to thrive. Most likely diagnosis?",
    "options": [
      "a) Allergic rhinitis",
      "b) Nasal polyps",
      "c) Adenoid hypertrophy",
      "d) Laryngomalacia",
      "e) Peritonsillar abscess"
    ],
    "answer": "c) Adenoid hypertrophy"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are seeing a five years old child with acute asthma. Which one of the following is correct?",
    "options": [
      "a) Oxygen is only needed in the presence of cyanosis",
      "b) Nebulized Salbutamol should be given initially",
      "c) Hydrocortisone is to be given only if patient not improving",
      "d) Chest X- Ray is routinely requested",
      "e) Antibiotic administration is essential"
    ],
    "answer": "b) Nebulized Salbutamol should be given initially"
  }
]